Lesson 10 Silicon valley
硅谷
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
anarchy: n.  无政府状态，混乱
What does the computer industry thrive on apart from anarchy?
除了无政府状态外,计算机工业还赖何兴旺?
Technology trends may push Silicon Valley back to the future.
技术的发展趋势有可能把硅谷重新推向未来.
circuit: n.  线路，电路
Carver Mead,a pioneer in integrated circuits
卡弗.米德--集成电路的一位先驱,aa
California: n.  加利福尼亚（美国州名）
and a professor of computer science at the California Institute of Technology,
加州理工学院的计算机教授--
workstation: n.  工作站
notes there are now workstations that enable engineers to design,
注意到,现在有些计算机工作站使工程师可以在他们的办公桌上设计、
chip: n.  芯片，集成电路片，集成块
test and produce chips right on their desks,
试验和生产芯片,
newsletter: n.  时事通讯, Macintosh: n.  苹果机，一种个人电脑
much the way and editor creates a newsletter on a Macintosh.
就像一位编辑在苹果机上编出一份时事通讯一样.
chip: n.  芯片，集成电路片，集成块
As the time and cost of making a chip drop to a few days and a few hundred dollars,
由于制造一块芯片的时间已缩短至几天,费用也只有几百美元,
engineers may soon be free to let their imaginations soar
因此,工程技术人员可能很快就可以充分发挥他们的想象力,
penalize: v.  处罚，惩罚
without being penalized by expensive failures.
而不会因失败而造成经济上的损失.
Mead predicts that inventors
米德预言发明者
chip: n.  芯片，集成电路片，集成块, customize: v.  按顾客具体需要制造
will be able to perfe- ct powerful customized chips over a weekend at the office--
可以在办公室用一个周末生产出完美、功能强劲的定制芯片--
spawn: v.  引起，酿成
spawning a new generation of garage start-ups
--造就新一代从汽车间起家的技术人员,
and giving the U.S. a jump on its foreign rivals in getting new product to market fast
在把产品推向市场方面使美国把它的外国对手们打个措手不及.
'We've got more garages with smart people,' Mead observes
"我们有更多的汽车间, 而那里有许多聪明人," 米德说.
anarchy: n.  无政府状态，混乱
'We really thrive on anarchy.'
"我们确实是靠这种无政府状态发展起来的."
oriental: n.  东方人
And on Asians. Already,orientals and Asian Americans,
依靠的还有亚洲人.东方人和亚裔美国人，
constitute: v.  构成
constitute the majority of the engineering staffs at many Valley firms.
是硅谷许多公司中工程技术员的主力.
And Chinese,Korean, Filipino and Indian engineers
中国、韩国、菲律宾和印度的工程师
California: n.  加利福尼亚（美国州名）, drove: n.  群
are graduating in droves from California's colleges.
一批批地从加州的大学毕业.
As the heads of next-generation start-ups,
作为新崛起一代的带头人,
innovator: n.  发明者
these Asian innovators can draw on customs and languages
亚裔发明家可以凭借他们在习惯和语言上的优势,
forge: v.  发展
to forge tighter links with crucial Pacific Rim markets.
与关键的太平洋沿岸市场建立起更加牢固的联系.
For instance,Alex Au,a Stanford Ph.D.from Hong Kong,has set up a Taiwan factory
比如说,亚历克斯.奥,一位来自香港的斯坦福大学博士,已经在台湾建厂,
chip: n.  芯片，集成电路片，集成块
to challenge Japan's near lock on the memorychip market.
对日本在内存条市场上近似垄断的局面提出了挑战。
California: n.  加利福尼亚（美国州名）
India-born N.Damodar Reddy's tiny California company ,
印度出生的N.达莫达.雷迪经营的小小的加州公司，
chip: n.  芯片，集成电路片，集成块, Kansas: n.  堪萨斯（美国州名）
reopened an At&T chip plant in Kansas City last spring
去春在堪萨斯城重新启用了美国电话电报公司的一家芯片工厂,
Missouri: n.  密苏里（美国州名）
with financing from the state of Missouri.
并从密苏里州获取了财政上的支持.
Before it becomes a retirement village,
在硅谷变成一个退休村之前,
Silicon Valley may prove a classroom for building a global business.
它很可能成为建立全球商业的一个教学场地.